# NAVEEN KUMAR SOURIRAJ ANTHUVAN

**Software Engineer** 

<u>Git Hub</u>

Mail Me +91-9995908901 +91-9384985436

+91-9384985436 Plot No.8, Senthamizh Nagar, Indra Nagar, Near New Railway st, Kanchipuram, 631502.

#### **TECHNOLOGIES**

- Node.js
- React.js
- Next.js
- Express.js
- Mongo DB
- GIT, CI/CD
- API Integration
- HTML/CSS, SCSS, LCSS.
- Bootstrap, Mui, etc.
- Agile Methodology

## **CERTIFICATIONS**

AWS Developer.

React.js, Node.js, JavaScript, HTML/CSS.

Core Java and J2EE.

## **SKILLS**

- Developing React projects with reusable and scalable react components based on the requirements.
- Ability to solve challenging problems while developing.
- Identifying bugs and errors with minimal time and fixing it.
- Integrating APIs with react applications to achieve CRUD operations.
- Efficiently able to use Git to manage code base and version control.
- Create and manages GitHub actions and other pipelines.
- Ability to customize plugins like Bootstrap and Mui components.

#### EDUCATION

Bachelor in Aeronautical engineering -Jeppiaar engineering college Anna University 2012-2016

# **PROFILE**

Enthusiastic software engineer with an overall 4+ years of experience in working closely with development team to create and manage readable, reusable, scalable, packageable react components to achieve the business requirements. Creates user interactive user interfaces and validates the date based on the client requirements and passes it across the project and API end points. Responsible for maintaining clean code base with GIT and version control. Responsible to interact/Integrate both the Client and server applications to make the project a full-fledged product.

## **EXPERIENCE**

Software engineer | EMIS Health / Chennai / May 2023—Till Date My role is to understand the business requirements provided the documentation by the clients and find business logic based on the requirements, create and manage scalable and re-usable react components respect to the CRUD operations and manage the development documentation for knowledge of other developers. Effective interaction with the QA team to make sure the client's requirements and development are aligned in the same track. Very efficient in GIT commands to manage the Code base and versions. Create and manages pipelines for CI/CD, pr checks and other coding standards.

**Software engineer |** Chateaux / Bangalore / Dec 2021 – May 2023. VCheck24 is a service provider, provides customizable program setup allows the VCheck24 platform to be used on a wide range of clients. Standard location tracking coupled with random video check-in monitoring can allow supervision officers and bail agents to keep a virtual "eye" on program participants. For re-entry clientele, zones triggered VChecks and scheduled inclusion zones monitor client arrival and leave times.

**UI Developer** | CloudNow tech LLC / Chennai / Sep 2021 – Dec 2021 My responsibilities are to understand the requirements and select the correct approach to create react components.

Interacting with the development team to develop the UI based on the CRUD operation with reusable and scalable

thoughts in mind. Create documentation for future reference.

Junior Software Engineer | iBridge LLC / Bangalore / Jul 2020 – Sep 2021 I had been developing web applications with various tech like php, JavaScript, Next.js, React.js. I had been responsible for maintaining the versions of the project/product with git hub/lab. Responsible for maintaining services in the react application to manage the CRUD operations.